<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Electrostate</title>
    <link>https://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Electrostate</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:36:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Roundup December 2025</title>
      <link>https://example.org/blog/video-game-roundup-december-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:36:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/blog/video-game-roundup-december-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;video-game-roundup&#34;&gt;Video Game Roundup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a view of the games I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;kotor-2&#34;&gt;KOTOR 2&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mainlined this game in early december. Beat it in a week. It&amp;rsquo;s a weird, broken thing - but fun! Playing it again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;kotor-1&#34;&gt;KOTOR 1&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After failing to get into it in 2024, I&amp;rsquo;ve become addicted this month. Playing on Switch. Beat it before the end of the month, and boy does the light side ending just not hit right. That whole game is/can be deeper than it lets on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="video-game-roundup">Video Game Roundup</h1>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a view of the games I&rsquo;ve been playing recently.</p>
<h3 id="kotor-2">KOTOR 2</h3>
<p>I mainlined this game in early december. Beat it in a week. It&rsquo;s a weird, broken thing - but fun! Playing it again.</p>
<h3 id="kotor-1">KOTOR 1</h3>
<p>After failing to get into it in 2024, I&rsquo;ve become addicted this month. Playing on Switch. Beat it before the end of the month, and boy does the light side ending just not hit right. That whole game is/can be deeper than it lets on.</p>
<h3 id="stonks-9800">Stonks 9800</h3>
<p>Got really into this, and now I&rsquo;m very rich in game! But now it&rsquo;s the &rsquo;90s and the economy sucks, so I tihnk I&rsquo;ll stop playing until 1.0 hits.</p>
<h3 id="mars-horizon-1">Mars Horizon 1</h3>
<p>Kinda turn based, space agency style game - fun. Want to put more time into it.</p>
<h3 id="nuclear-throne">Nuclear Throne???</h3>
<p>The GOAT has returned, and more powerful than ever. Nuclear Throne is such an iconic 2010&rsquo;s indie game, glad it got update 100 and there is a bit more buzz around it.</p>
<h3 id="battlefront-classic-collection">Battlefront Classic Collection</h3>
<p>Flawed but playing on Switch. Kinda cool to be playing these games on a console again, they work much better with a controller. I&rsquo;ll futz with it for a while, I&rsquo;m sure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: Fishing Games</title>
      <link>https://example.org/blog/fish-game-db-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/blog/fish-game-db-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-no-longer-need-a-bigger-boat&#34;&gt;We no longer need a bigger boat&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fishing games appear to have moved past their prime. In the below graph (from &lt;a href=&#34;https://rawg.io/apidocs&#34;&gt;rawg api data&lt;/a&gt;) you can see that 2021 and 2022 were the clear highs for this type of game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://trinitui.github.io/electrostate_files/images/fishing_games_w_reviews.png&#34; alt=&#34;Games with reviews&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What you can also see is that very few, if any, of these games have garnered any attention. Maybe 5% of a given year&amp;rsquo;s games are played enough for the RAWG community to review.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="we-no-longer-need-a-bigger-boat">We no longer need a bigger boat</h2>
<p>Fishing games appear to have moved past their prime. In the below graph (from <a href="https://rawg.io/apidocs">rawg api data</a>) you can see that 2021 and 2022 were the clear highs for this type of game.</p>
<p><img src="https://trinitui.github.io/electrostate_files/images/fishing_games_w_reviews.png" alt="Games with reviews"></p>
<p>What you can also see is that very few, if any, of these games have garnered any attention. Maybe 5% of a given year&rsquo;s games are played enough for the RAWG community to review.</p>
<p>Further, the clear king of fishing games, Dredge, was released in the later half of 2023, well beyond the end of the boom.</p>
<p>So what happened in 2013 or 2016 that led to such a boom? I have some thoughs below.</p>
<h3 id="2013-apps">2013: Apps</h3>
<p>2013 is about when mobile gaming is really breaking through. More people have phones that can play games, and app stores have made it trivially easy to try games out.</p>
<p><img src="https://trinitui.github.io/electrostate_files/images/platforms_data.png" alt="platforms"></p>
<p>This effect started in 2010, but started picking up in 2013. But by 2016, something else happened in gaming that, along with mobile phone adoption, made fishing an attractive feature in games.</p>
<h3 id="2016-stardew-valley">2016: Stardew Valley</h3>
<p>Certainly some of the increase in fishing games are due to Stardew Valley, which was a real paradigm shift for indie games. From my perspective, indies moved from Fez to something less rareified, more authentic, and more free. Stardew Valley helped to popularize a movement and cement indies as a powerful new stream in gaming. And you see that, post 2016. There have been few AA+ releases that are focused on or adjacent to fishing&hellip; it&rsquo;s all indies!</p>
<h3 id="so-what-happened">So&hellip; what happened?</h3>
<p>Maybe there&rsquo;s an issue with this data. It&rsquo;s strange that in 2024 and 2025 there are no mobile games included, so perhaps there&rsquo;s a data issue. More analysis of this data source will be needed, in future posts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Roundup Late November 2025</title>
      <link>https://example.org/blog/podcast-roundup-late-november-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 07:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/blog/podcast-roundup-late-november-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcast-roundup&#34;&gt;Podcast Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A quick overview of what I&amp;rsquo;m listening to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hardcore-gaming-101s-top-47k-games&#34;&gt;Hardcore Gaming 101&amp;rsquo;s Top 47k games&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve really only had time to listen to their coverage of some games this month. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a big month for me to get into podcasts for some reason? Probably life stuff getting in the way. But these guys are great!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="podcast-roundup">Podcast Roundup</h2>
<p>A quick overview of what I&rsquo;m listening to</p>
<h3 id="hardcore-gaming-101s-top-47k-games">Hardcore Gaming 101&rsquo;s Top 47k games</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;ve really only had time to listen to their coverage of some games this month. It hasn&rsquo;t been a big month for me to get into podcasts for some reason? Probably life stuff getting in the way. But these guys are great!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Roundup Late November 2025</title>
      <link>https://example.org/blog/video-game-roundup-late-november-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 16:43:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/blog/video-game-roundup-late-november-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;video-game-roundup&#34;&gt;Video Game Roundup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a view of the games I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;europa-universalis-v&#34;&gt;Europa Universalis V&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They finally made a decent followup to Vicky 2, and put it in a nearly over-designed game. Love it, love playing it, love not know what the heck is going on, and love that these are the early days and more content is coming. This is a wonderful game on it&amp;rsquo;s own, and a fantastic foundation for future content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="video-game-roundup">Video Game Roundup</h1>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a view of the games I&rsquo;ve been playing recently.</p>
<h3 id="europa-universalis-v">Europa Universalis V</h3>
<p>They finally made a decent followup to Vicky 2, and put it in a nearly over-designed game. Love it, love playing it, love not know what the heck is going on, and love that these are the early days and more content is coming. This is a wonderful game on it&rsquo;s own, and a fantastic foundation for future content.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s also worth noting that they answered the question of &ldquo;What could you possibly do after 12 years of EU4 and it&rsquo;s updates&rdquo; with a pretty amazing response - take the bones of EU4 but make it a deeper simulation, and in so doing add mechanics and features that alow the game to grow laterally. Pretty clever stuff. BUT - I wonder how much longer Paradox can keep this up?</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been exploring the game with these nations:</p>
<ul>
<li>Holland</li>
<li>Livonian Order</li>
<li>Egypt</li>
</ul>
<p>One of the strengths of EU5 is that it takes the flavor and interesting mechanics/elements that you can find not playing in Europe from EU4 - this is a huge change from when EU4 went live and Europe was the focus.</p>
<p>Another strength is that playing a small nation is fun! You can literally build it up from scratch!</p>
<h3 id="wall-world-2">Wall World 2</h3>
<p>Games like this are awesome to find. You need to play so many subpar or just ok games to find the indie game like this that really hits in a unique way.</p>
<p>On it&rsquo;s surface, it&rsquo;s a dome keeper clone, but that comparison only goes so far. There&rsquo;s a story, there&rsquo;s story missions, and a more meaningful upgrade path than dome keeper has. This is yet another hit for the &ldquo;games with yellow as an accent color&rdquo; category in 2025 (after Citizen Sleeper 2).</p>
<h3 id="coal-llc">Coal LLC</h3>
<p>What if indie games were just flash games???</p>
<h3 id="openttd">OpenTTD</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been fooling around with different scenarios and ideas, but nothing has really caught me at this point.</p>
<h3 id="openfrontio">OpenFront.io</h3>
<p>In my mind this is a flash game, even though it really isn&rsquo;t. This is a flash game take on Risk, it&rsquo;s fun and arcadey and hits a weird &ldquo;&ldquo;&ldquo;strategy&rdquo;&rdquo;&rdquo; game itch that you need sometimes. Sometime you just need a trashy game to spend time with, and this has been that.</p>
<h3 id="battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</h3>
<p>Been playing this on and off, but it can be hard to find time to devote to this with so much other good stuff out there</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Roundup Late October 2025</title>
      <link>https://example.org/blog/podcast-roundup-late-october-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:11:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/blog/podcast-roundup-late-october-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;podcast-roundup&#34;&gt;Podcast Roundup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A quick overview of what I&amp;rsquo;m listening to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hardcore-gaming-101s-top-47k-games&#34;&gt;Hardcore Gaming 101&amp;rsquo;s Top 47k games&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to this one for maybe almost six months? It&amp;rsquo;s a good show for commuting, and I always like hearing people explain why they are passionate about different games. It&amp;rsquo;s rare that a game that came out in the past 10 years is covered, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to hear about obscure games and their stories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="podcast-roundup">Podcast Roundup</h1>
<p>A quick overview of what I&rsquo;m listening to</p>
<h3 id="hardcore-gaming-101s-top-47k-games">Hardcore Gaming 101&rsquo;s Top 47k games</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been listening to this one for maybe almost six months? It&rsquo;s a good show for commuting, and I always like hearing people explain why they are passionate about different games. It&rsquo;s rare that a game that came out in the past 10 years is covered, so it&rsquo;s good to hear about obscure games and their stories.</p>
<h3 id="side-story">Side Story</h3>
<p>Austin Walker&rsquo;s new pod. About games. He&rsquo;s a great personality and hearing him talk about games again is great. I don&rsquo;t listen religously, but when it pops up in my feed and I have time, I listen in. It&rsquo;s chill, and they talk about games that I don&rsquo;t usually play, so it&rsquo;s a great time.</p>
<h3 id="a-more-civilized-age">A More Civilized Age</h3>
<p>This pod was my entry drug back into podcasts. I listen to podcasts all the time because of this show - finding it in 2023 was like discovering a whole new world. Their current unit on KOTOR II I&rsquo;m not really feeling - I should have played the game alongside them but didn&rsquo;t - but I&rsquo;ll dip in more in the future when their unit changes. Excited to see what comes next from this show.</p>
<h3 id="tapcaf-transmissions">Tapcaf Transmissions</h3>
<p>I don&rsquo;t listen to new ep&rsquo;s, but I do listen to their older shows on EU Star War books when I finish those books. They aren&rsquo;t the best at recapping books, but it&rsquo;s still entertaining.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Roundup Late October 2025</title>
      <link>https://example.org/blog/video-game-roundup-late-october-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:42:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/blog/video-game-roundup-late-october-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;video-game-roundup&#34;&gt;Video Game Roundup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a view of the games I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;battlefield-6&#34;&gt;Battlefield 6&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I try to dip into this when I can. While I&amp;rsquo;m not happy with the state of AAA games, my one exception is the Battlefield series. I&amp;rsquo;ve been hooked since I played 3 back in 2013 and though I haven&amp;rsquo;t played all since that released, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to dip in when I can. I think 2042 ended up in a cool place when I re-visited it this year, and 6 is legitimately good. Excited to play more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="video-game-roundup">Video Game Roundup</h1>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a view of the games I&rsquo;ve been playing recently.</p>
<h3 id="battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</h3>
<p>I try to dip into this when I can. While I&rsquo;m not happy with the state of AAA games, my one exception is the Battlefield series. I&rsquo;ve been hooked since I played 3 back in 2013 and though I haven&rsquo;t played all since that released, I&rsquo;ve tried to dip in when I can. I think 2042 ended up in a cool place when I re-visited it this year, and 6 is legitimately good. Excited to play more.</p>
<h3 id="ascension-deckbuilding-game">Ascension Deckbuilding Game</h3>
<p>Ascension used to be me and my friend&rsquo;s go-to game back in College. Now, I&rsquo;m having a ton of fun playing it digitally. While I want to play with other people, I haven&rsquo;t really found a group that wants to play it as much as I do. For now, this version of it is enough.</p>
<h3 id="openttd">OpenTTD</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;m back on it again. I feel like when I finally got into this game late last year some unholy seal had been breached and my life would never be the same again. Like when you play Minecraft for the first time. I&rsquo;m high on the scenarios this time - playing a Middle Earth one (very cool) and one based on MA (even cooler) and I&rsquo;m having a blast.</p>
<h4 id="dipping-into">Dipping into</h4>
<ol>
<li>Mars Logisitcs - this is a fun lego-type game that I need to put more time into</li>
<li>Anno 1800 - What a beautiful, overwrought thing they created here. I need to simultaneously play Victoria 3 and sip London Fog tea.</li>
</ol>
<h4 id="looking-ahead">Looking ahead</h4>
<ol>
<li>EU5&hellip;</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Dreams</title>
      <link>https://example.org/blog/solar-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 18:29:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/blog/solar-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-sun-shines-everywhere&#34;&gt;The Sun Shines Everywhere&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of solar around me. By that, I mean take a look at a new country-club type place in town that the town is generating energy off of. It&amp;rsquo;s been installed for over a year and the combo of solar power and batteries has really brought down costs in Medfield.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/59552faaff7c50fb8b38c931/15436b60-9522-41a7-921a-2de429bd3826/DJI_0868.JPG?format=1500w&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I consider Medfield to be typical of suburbia in the greater Boston area, and so what is accomplishable here should be portable to lots of different places in the region. Some solutions will be easier to implement than others, but I think this town is a good yardstick for what the region can get on board with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-sun-shines-everywhere">The Sun Shines Everywhere</h1>
<p>There&rsquo;s a lot of solar around me. By that, I mean take a look at a new country-club type place in town that the town is generating energy off of. It&rsquo;s been installed for over a year and the combo of solar power and batteries has really brought down costs in Medfield.</p>
<p><img src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/59552faaff7c50fb8b38c931/15436b60-9522-41a7-921a-2de429bd3826/DJI_0868.JPG?format=1500w" alt="image"></p>
<p>I consider Medfield to be typical of suburbia in the greater Boston area, and so what is accomplishable here should be portable to lots of different places in the region. Some solutions will be easier to implement than others, but I think this town is a good yardstick for what the region can get on board with.</p>
<p>The region needs to get on board more - not just from a &ldquo;Save the Earth&rdquo; perspective, but from the real practicalities of Solar power. The sun shines everywhere, all day, and once you get that panel installed it&rsquo;s only a matter of time before it pays itself off. And then you are using the sun to power your car, or your AC, or anything else. It&rsquo;s a powerful idea - and we need to embrace it here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting a blog</title>
      <link>https://example.org/blog/starting-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:17:03 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/blog/starting-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since March 2020 I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to journal about life, and the past five and a half years have just been full of reasons why a journal of these times is so important.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But why the name? I&amp;rsquo;m really excited by what is going on in electrification, specifically with solar panels taking off in a huge way over the past two to three years. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this planet&amp;rsquo;s journey to a more solar powered future is a prominent theme to this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="why">Why?</h2>
<p>Since March 2020 I&rsquo;ve wanted to journal about life, and the past five and a half years have just been full of reasons why a journal of these times is so important.</p>
<p>But why the name? I&rsquo;m really excited by what is going on in electrification, specifically with solar panels taking off in a huge way over the past two to three years. I&rsquo;m hoping this planet&rsquo;s journey to a more solar powered future is a prominent theme to this blog.</p>
<p>This is short and sweet, but it&rsquo;s the start - I&rsquo;ll take to you(?) in a bit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
